Preet Gupta

□ preetgupta189@gmail.com
□

+46764400981 Stockholm, Sweden in Linkedln Github



Al Engineer with a Master's in Artificial Intelligence and experience in data analysis (cleaning, processing, analyzing, and visualization) and data science (clustering, classification, and forecasting) as well as data modeling and data warehousing. Proficient in utilizing machine learning and deep learning techniques to analyze complex data with large volumes into valuable business insights.

EDUCATION

Master's in Artificial Intelligence, *Stockholm University*

08/2023 – present | Stockholm, Sweden

Currently pursuing my Master's in Artificial Intelligence at Stockholm University, where I'm gaining exposure in Data Mining, Big Data with NoSQL databases, Machine Learning, Deep Learning and NLP.

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering,

08/2019 – 06/2023 | Mumbai, India

Ramrao Adik Institute of Technology

CGPA: 9.00/10

Relevant courses in Computer Engineering include Operating Systems, Software Engineering, Database Management Systems, and Cloud Computing, showcasing foundational expertise in key disciplines.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Al Intern, Wyzbo

10/2022 – 03/2023 | Pune, India

I was involved in a project developing a scanning system to find keywords in resumes and match them to job descriptions, managing large datasets. Additionally, I played a role in designing and implementing algorithms to enhance the accuracy of keyword extraction

Machine Learning Intern, Knowledge Solutions India

06/2021 – 09/2021 | Mumbai, India

I was involved in managing data cleaning and preprocessing for large medical datasets, as well as building machine learning models to predict cardiovascular heart disease diagnosis.

♠ SKILLS

Programming languages (Python, SQL, C, C++, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Prolog)

Framework and Libraries (Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Sklearn, OpenCV, Keras, Tensorflow, Streamlit)

Data Visualization Tools (PowerBI, Tableau) • **Microsoft Office** (Word, Powerpoint, Excel, Outlook)

Languages (English (Fluent), Hindi (Fluent), Swedish (Learning))

PROJECTS

Stock Price Prediction ∅

This project uses Stacked LSTM deep learning to predict stock prices with historical data from Tiingo, helping investors make informed decisions by evaluating model performance in financial markets.

Movie Recommender System *⊘*

Created a recommender system presenting customised movie recommendations based on user interests using advanced machine learning algorithms.

Credit Card Fraud Detection ⊘

The model is created to examine the features and trends in deceptive transactions with the aim of spotting possible signs of fraudulent behavior.

PUBLICATIONS

Identification of Fake Products using Blockchain, IEEE Xplore ⊘

Developed a blockchain-based QR code system to authenticate original products, enhancing consumer safety and mitigating financial and health risks associated with counterfeit goods.